你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第十一集
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Nonopig  阿好  沙沙A  紫玉  天朝直属
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   擦擦
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监：阿好
获取档案
2010年7月
获取关联文件
纽约警局
纽约警局档案  2010年7月
会话分析
语言识别
911  有什么紧急状况
911. What is your emergency?
我是地铁操作员4827号
This is subway train operator 4827.
发生了一起事故
There's been an accident.
获取档案
2010年7月
大西洋大道站
我没能及时叫停列车
I couldn't stop the train in time,
撞到了一个孩子
and I hit a kid.
他可能是被人推的
I think he might have been pushed.
张嘴
Open.
把他们隔离起来
I want 'em held in isolation.
不得联系外界  不得接触律师
No contact: not with their lawyers,
不得接触彼此
not with each other,
不得接触任何人
not with anybody.
事关国家安全
This is a matter of national security.
他们是恐怖分子吗
They're terrorists?
我看他们更像投行家
They look more like investment bankers to me.
典狱长  其中三人可能是
Well, warden, three of them may be.
但其中有一个是我追捕的人中
But one of them is the most dangerous criminal
最最危险的罪犯
I've ever pursued.
我有权不经起诉拘留他们72小时
I can hold them for 72 hours without charging them,
我也正意如此
and I fully intend to.
你就只有72小时
Then you have 72 hours.
这里是纽约里克岛  不是关塔那摩
This is Rikers, not Guantanamo.
你不打算审讯他们吗
You don't plan on asking them any questions?
别担心  卡特
Don't worry, Carter.
我们有新罗歇尔拿到的DNA证据
We've got the DNA evidence from New Rochelle,
有烧毁的车中拿到的血液
we got the blood from the burned car,
多亏了你  还有指纹
and, thanks to you, fingerprints.
他跑不掉了
He's ours.
为什么我早就知道联邦机构也难你不倒呢
How did I know the federal government would be no match for you?
如果你被发现还带着手机
As I suspect it might be compromising for you
恐怕要罪加一等了  所以我简言吧
to be found with a phone, I'll be brief.
情况在控制中  约翰
The matter is in hand, John.
我们会救你出来
We'll get you out of there.
是我太冒险了
I took too many risks.
是我的错  我来处理
It's my fault. I'll handle it.
听我说
Listen to me.
我为现下的情形做过预案了
I made preparations for a scenario like this.
72小时后  你就自由了
In 72 hours, you will walk free.
如果又出现号码呢
What if another number comes up?
遗憾的是  正如我所说
Unfortunately, as I told you,
号码从不停止
they never stop coming.
我会尽力解决
I'll have to manage as best I can.
诚挚地希望我们下次对话时
I sincerely hope our next conversation is
环境会好点儿
under better circumstances.
保持联系
I'll be in touch.
我是斯威夫特先生
My name is Mr. Swift.
你们的代课老师
I'm your substitute teacher.
本瑟姆女士临时得到机会
Ms. Benthem received a last-minute opportunity
参加在毛伊岛举行的免费教学研讨会
to attend an all-expenses-paid teaching seminar in Maui.
根据本瑟姆女士的教学计划
I see in Ms. Benthem's lesson plan
今天我们要做
that today we're doing...
加法
addition.
这不对啊
That can't be right.
那是外加作业  惩罚
It's busywork, punishment.
要我们把从一到一百的数字相加
We're supposed to add the numbers from 1 to 100.
数学可不是惩罚
Math is not punishment.
十八世纪后期
You know, in the late 18th century,
有位数学天才名叫卡尔・弗里德里克・高斯
there was a math prodigy named Carl Friedrich Gauss
他当时与你们一样  遇到这一乏味的问题
who was faced with the same tedious problem that you are.
他就此想出了一个办法
He figured a way around it.
从一加到一百
One to a hundred.
有人想来试一下高斯的解法吗
Who'd like to take a crack at working out Gauss' equation?
有人吗
Anybody?
菲普斯先生
Mr. Phipps?
老实说  斯威夫特先生
I got to be honest, "Mr. Swifty",
"弗里德里克"之后我啥也没听见
you lost me at "Friedrich."
给你个提示
I'll give you a hint.
-弗斯科  -早上好  警探
- Fusco. - Good morning, Detective.
相信你已经收到我的邮件了
I trust that you received my email?
还有布鲁克林科学学校的全员登记表
And the entire roll call for Brooklyn Science.
你要尽可能告诉我关于迦勒・菲普斯的一切
I need you to tell me everything you can about Caleb Phipps.
跟纽约警察打过几次交道
Couple run-ins with the NYPD.
典型小屁孩犯的事儿
Typical kid stuff.
-没啥突出的  -当然
- Nothing exceptional. - I'll say.
绩点2.6
2.6 GPA
测试成绩正好处于中间
and test scores that sit squarely in the mid-range.
整节课都在笔记本上胡写乱画
He spent my whole class doodling in his notebook.
还在吗
Hey, you still there?
请继续
Please continue.
有件不同寻常的事情
One thing did come up.
迦勒有个哥哥瑞安
Caleb had an older brother Ryan,
两年前死于一起地铁事故
killed two years ago in a subway accident.
那孩子当时喝醉了
Kid was drunk.
滑下轨道  被撞了
Slipped on the tracks and got clipped.
太可怕了
Sounds awful.
其他细节呢
Any further details?
我去把事故报告调出来
I'll pull the incident report.
迦勒现在跟他妈妈生活在一起
Now Caleb lives alone with his mom.
她在肯辛通工作  做行政助理
She's an administrative assistant in Kensington.
迦勒
Hey, Caleb.
周六你去那派对吗
You going to that party Saturday?
不去  不是我的菜
No, that's not my kind of thing.
再说了  我要出城
Besides, I'm heading out of town.
出趟门
Taking a trip.
迦勒・菲普斯
强制配对
失败
朱丽安
强制配对
完成
你喜欢哪个
[兴奋剂]安非他明还是[兴奋剂]利他林
那丫头就是个颜控
没完没了的短信
They never seem to stop texting.
特意为你而照
我像到了外星球
Beginning to feel like I'm on another planet.
习惯吧
Get used to it.
十年后这些外星人就要占领地球了
Their planet's gonna be running ours in about ten years.
现在的高中可不一样了
High schools are different nowadays.
帮派斗殴  毒品搜查  未婚先孕
Gang fights, drug searches, and pregnancies.
这孩子可能卷进任何麻烦
This kid could be into anything.
毒品问题你确实没夸张
You weren't exaggerating about the drug problem.
现在的孩子都大不一样了
Kids ain't what they used to be.
在那边小心  老兄
Be careful in there, pal.
我都懒得问了
I-I won't even ask.
最好不过了
Probably best.
再说  我们还有更紧要的事情得讨论
Besides, we have more urgent matters to discuss.
关在里克岛的那位
Our friend in Rikers.
情况在控制中了
I have the situation in hand.
我不想要你越界去
I don't want you crossing some kind of line to do--
这个
This?
网络数据也删除了
Already deleted them from the network too.
你说的那个界
That line you're talking about,
我很早就越过了
I crossed it a long time ago.
现在我们得处理DNA样本
Now we have to deal with the DNA sample.
联调局把它放在纽约一家安全实验室里
FBI keeps it in a secure lab here in New York.
我知道怎么做
I know what to do.
但我需要你提供点东西
But I'm gonna need a couple things from you.
我是劳顿校长
This is Principal Lawton,
提醒大家
reminding you
布鲁克林科学人文学校
that the Brooklyn School Of Science & Humanities
五点准时闭校
closes promptly at 5:00 p.m.
谢谢
Thank you.
斯威夫特先生
Mr. Swift.
麻烦聊两句
A word, please.
我听说
It has come to my attention
你教本瑟姆女士班里的学生
that you tried to show Ms. Benthem's students
如何规避她布置的作业
how to get around one of her assignments.
那作业似乎没什么意义
Well, the assignment seemed a bit remedial.
-我希望能教  -教课是本瑟姆女士的工作
- I was hoping to teach-- - Teaching is Ms. Benthem's job.
你的工作是监督她的学生
Your job is to ensure that her students
完成她布置的作业
do the work that she prepared.
甭理劳顿
Don't sweat Lawton.
她觉得要能甩掉学生和老师
She thinks schools would run better
学校能运转得更加良好呢
if they just got rid of the students and teachers.
克里斯・贝克纳  教电脑科学的
Chris Beckner, computer science.
哈罗德・斯威夫特
Harold Swift.
-很高兴认识理想主义者  -不不  我不是
- Nice to meet an idealist. - No, no, not me.
要我说最好全都网络化
Throw all this stuff online, I say.
让我穿着裤衩讲课
Let me teach in my boxers.
放开手脚吧  伙计
Run wild, man.
我相信我会的
I believe I will.
校长办公室
怎样  弗斯科警探
Yes, Detective Fusco?
有新消息要告诉我吗
Do you have some new information for me?
没错  确实有
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I do.
我查看了他哥哥的死亡报告
I took a look at the report of his brother's death.
-迦勒是唯一的目击者  -他在现场
- Caleb was the only witness. - He was there?
他哥哥就死在他面前
His brother died right in front of him?
没错  但事有蹊跷
Yeah, but something's not right.
我查阅了当晚所有的事故报告
I looked at every incident report that night.
站警向调度请求支援
The transit cop called for a backup, to dispatch,
随后又取消了申请
and then cancelled the request.
为什么站警会取消支援申请呢
Why would a policeman rescind a request for backup?
我也想知道
That's what I'm trying to figure out.
我正等着调度报告给我答案呢
I'm waiting on the transcripts to find out why.
也许我该去见见迦勒的母亲
Maybe it's time I go meet Caleb's mom
看看他的家庭生活如何
and find out what his home life is like.
有意思
Interesting.
迦勒最近一次全国学习能力测试水平
Caleb's latest National Aptitude Test score
正好是50%
is exactly 50%.
这种机率小到不可能
A statistically improbable score.
除非是故意的
Unless you try to get it.
迦勒知道每道题的答案
You see, Caleb knew the answer to every question.
但他刻意有选择的答题
But he chose only to fill in every other one.
我不明白  他故意的吗
I don't get it. He tanked on purpose?
为什么要隐藏自己是天才呢
Why would you want to hide the fact you're a genius?
浪费时间
到底为什么呢
Why, indeed?
迦勒  聊两句
Caleb, a word?
我发现了这个
I couldn't help but notice this.
无疑冒犯  斯威夫特先生
No offense, Mr. Swift,
你混到要翻垃圾了吗
but now you're going through the garbage?
π
Pi.
有人知道是什么意思吗
Can any of you tell me what it means?
提出问题我也接受
I'll settle for an intelligent question here.
我朋友有个问题  斯威夫特先生
My friend has a question, Mr. Swift.
学这有什么用
"What is any of this good for,
我们几时会用得上
and when would we ever use it?"
我来告诉你
Let me show you.
π
Pi.
圆周长与其直径之比
The ratio of the circumference of a circle to its diameter.
这是开始
And this is just the beginning.
后面一直有
It keeps on going.
无穷无尽
Forever.
永不重复
Without ever repeating.
就是说在这串数字中
Which means that contained within this string of decimals
包含每种可能的组合
is every single other number.
你的生日
Your birth date,
储物柜密码
combination to your locker,
你的社保号码
your social security number.
都在其中某处
It's all in there somewhere.
如果把这些数字转换为字母
And if you convert these decimals into letters,
就能得到所有的单词
you would have every word that ever existed
无数种组合
in every possible combination.
你婴儿时发出的第一个音节
The first syllable you spoke as a baby,
你心上人的名字
the name of your latest crush,
你一辈子从始至终的故事
your entire life story from beginning to end.
我们做过或说过的每件事
Everything we ever say or do...
宇宙中所有无限的可能
all of the world's infinite possibilities rest
都在这个简单的圆中
within this one simple circle.
用这些信息做什么
Now what you do with that information...
它有什么用
what it's good for...
取决于你们
well, that would be up to you.
纽约警察  女士
NYPD, ma'am.
我们正在调查本地区发生的连环盗窃案
We're investigating a string of burglaries in the area.
想向住户了解下
Talking to residents about things
有否看到或听到什么
they might have seen or heard.
能否进去问您几个问题
Mind if I come in and ask you a few questions?
我已经迟到了
I'm running a little late.
你自己住吗
So you, uh, you live alone?
还有我儿子迦勒
With my son Caleb.
我们没多余的房间  迦勒睡沙发
We don't have a lot of room, so Caleb takes the couch.
工作电话  稍等一下
That's work. Just give me a sec.
你和你儿子最近注意到什么可疑情况吗
So you and your son see anything suspicious lately?
有什么陌生人出现吗
Any strange comings and goings?
引人注意的那种
Anyone who stands out?
我没什么印象
Nothing I can think of.
警察一年会来几次
Cops come a few times a year.
都是些家长里短
It's domestic stuff mostly.
有些家庭日子不好过  你懂的吧
Some families have it rough, you know?
是啊  我懂你的意思
Yeah, I know exactly what you mean.
谢谢
Thanks for your time.
怎样  警探
Yes, Detective?
我给你装了摄像头
I planted that webcam for you.
见了迦勒的母亲
Met Caleb's mom.
上班迟到  开门时摇摇晃晃
Late for work, rolling out the door with the shakes.
估计她酗酒
My guess is she's hitting the bottle.
难怪迦勒不在乎自己的成绩
No wonder Caleb doesn't care about his grades.
有那两个毒贩的消息吗
Anything new on our two dealers?
迭戈斯・奎兹和罗尼・山姆斯
Diego Velasquez and Ronnie Samms.
以前替一个叫洛伦佐的贩货
Used to deal for a guy by the name of Lorenzo.
那种人你肯定不想惹
Type of guy you don't wanna cross.
不过现在他们给一个新人卖命
But now they're working for some new up-and-comer
缉毒部门还没查出是谁
that narcotics hasn't been able to identify.
我跟你说  那学校绝对是雷区啊
I tell you, that school's a real minefield.
好的
Okay.
你不会说出去的对吧  头
Gonna keep your mouth shut, right, Chief?
当然
Yeah, sure.
就一点
Except to say this.
下次你们再想卖摇头丸
The next time you decide you want to deal E
给摆明了这辈子没买过的孩子时
to a kid who's clearly never bought in his entire life,
到楼下的储藏室去
do it in the locker room downstairs,
因为这二货一用
because this jumpy fool
就相当于脑门上直书大字"吸过毒啦"
is a neon sign shouting "Drugs Ahoy"...
头
Chief.
够了
That's enough!
除非你们想去校长办公室解决
Unless you want to settle this in the principal's office.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我不需要你帮忙  行不
I don't need your help...okay?
"黑客"曾指那些勤劳的编码员
"Hacker" used to refer to industrious coders
他们推动了现代电脑的发展
who pushed the boundaries of modern computing.
这名词随后变了味道
Then that word became misappropriated
指那些行为过界违法乱纪
by those who pushed the boundaries so far
最后要去坐牢的人了
that they ended up with jail time.
例如八十年代的凯文・米特尼克
Like Kevin Mitnick, back in the 1980s.
他只不过想看看系统如何运作
He was just trying to see how stuff worked.
米特尼克当时是在寻找系统漏洞
Mitnick was looking for flaws in the system.
他的手段犯了法
And he did so by breaking the law.
但他证明了漏洞在人  而非编码
But he proved people were the flaw, not the code.
现在他们花大钱请他
Now they're paying him millions
做那些当初害他蹲监狱的事
for the same thing that got him locked up in the first place.
或许最为臭名昭著的黑客
Perhaps the most notorious hacker of them all
是成功溜走的那位
was the one that got away.
当美国政府正试图
Back when Uncle Sam was trying
用铁栅栏框住刚刚萌芽的互联网
to maintain its iron grip on the budding internet--
或者说"阿帕网"  当时是这么叫的
or Arpanet, as it was known then--
这位黑客  编码员  侵入了系统
this hacker, this coder, hacked into the system
使其曝光
and laid its secrets bare,
让互联网成为公共平台
ensuring that the internet would become an open forum.
这名黑客厉害之处在于从未被抓住
Plus that hacker made his mark without ever getting busted.
没错
True.
无论是谁  此人仍逍遥在外
Whoever it was, that person's still out there.
我来问问那天才男孩
Hey, I'm checking on the boy genius.
不是说你  另外那个
Not you, the other one.
看来他编码颇有两下子
Turns out he's quite the little coder.
他正着手编写一个硕大的程序
He's been coding a massive program.
而且是手写  因为他家里都没电脑
In longhand, as he doesn't have a computer at home.
然后再写进实验室的电脑里
Then he writes it into a computer in the lab.
如果我发现的这部分编码
If the partial code I've discovered
真的是他作品的一部分
is a snapshot of his work...
那他正在发明的东西
what he's creating...
会震惊世界
could be groundbreaking.
弗斯科警探  能帮我个忙吗
Detective Fusco, can you do something for me?
我要你去跟踪迭戈和罗尼
I need you to follow Diego and Ronnie.
今天迦勒和他们吵了一架
Caleb had a run-in with them today
可能会出麻烦
that might lead to trouble.
-他们有什么恩怨吗  -难说
- Is there a history there? - Hard to tell.
但迦勒看上去
But Caleb seemed
对他们的毒品交易有很大兴趣
to take an outsized interest in their drug dealing.
如果有人暗中操控
If someone's pulling their strings,
我想知道那个人是谁
I'd like to know who.
芬奇  这个毒贩子  非常谨慎
Finch, whoever this drug dealer is, he's careful.
警探  你计划的第一步进行得如何
Detective, how goes phase one of your plan?
我收到了你寄来的包裹
I got the package you sent over,
但要我这浑水
but if I'm gonna wade in this pool,
我需要确切的数据
I need the right specs.
好的
Yeah.
正在发给你
Sending them to you now.
关在里克岛的那位就指望你了
Our friend in Rikers is counting on you.
血统:欧洲
身高:183-193厘米
瞳色:蓝色
发色:棕色
需排除的医疗情况:
囊性纤维化  遗传性血色沉着
-好的  -搞定他们  警探
- Okay. - Knock 'em dead, Detective.
他们根本不会知道自己怎么栽的
They won't know what hit 'em.
我想要
Hi, I'd like to have--
第一杯我请
the first one, on me.
你好吗
How are you doing?
谢了  不过  我想要的是
Thanks, but, I'm looking for something a little more...
特定的类型
specific.
弗斯科警探  那年轻人开始行动了
Detective Fusco, our young man is on the move.
载你回家吧
Give you a ride home?
我的车就停在那儿
Car is right down there.
好啊
I'd like that.
我得承认  你刚开始吓到我了
I have to admit, you kind of threw me at first.
一直不停地问我的生活背景
Asking all those questions about my background,
健康状况
my health.
我都弄不清是在调情呢
I couldn't tell whether we were flirtin'
还是在查病历
or fillin' out my medical history.
我很实际
I'm a practical girl.
喜欢先了解自己能进展到哪一步
I like to know what I'm getting into.
那我们
So are we...
今晚能有进展吗
getting into anything tonight?
我有
I am.
我不知道怎么回事  可是
I don't know what happened, but...
我都没喝很多酒
I didn't even have that much to drink.
张大嘴  好家伙
Open wide, big fella.
我一整晚都跟着这些毒资
I've been following this drug money all night.
迭戈和罗尼拿了一袋子
Diego and Ronnie handed a bagful of it
给了一个流浪汉  我跟着他
to a homeless guy, who I followed
钱被丢到一处转账的地方
till he dumped it off at a money transfer place.
那儿的工作人员把它
The worker there wired it
送到城另一头的钱行
to another money hub across town,
我赶到时刚巧看见
where I hoofed it over there just in time
另一个人来取现金
to see some other guy pick up the cash
然后扔进了皇冠高地这儿的一个邮箱
and drop it in a PO box right here in Crown Heights.
那位神秘的毒枭在洗钱
Our mysterious drug lord is laundering his money,
让它无源可溯
making it untraceable.
倒也并非无源可溯
Well, not untraceable enough.
来取这笔钱的人  就是我们要找的
Whoever comes in for this cash is our guy.
你在哪儿
Where are you anyway?
我正看着你呢
I'm looking at you.
你不是在跟着那孩子吗
Thought you were following the kid.
我是啊
I am.
-给你  先生  -谢谢
- Here you go, sir. - Thanks.
扯了大蛋了
Well, I'll be damned.
那位神秘毒枭就是迦勒
Our mystery drug lord is Caleb.
卷子批完了
Graded your quizzes.
有些同学挺认真的
Some of you have been paying attention.
迦勒  你可以考更好的
Caleb, I expected better.
-那孩子又怎么了  -迦勒刚收到信息
- What did the kid do now? - Caleb just got a message.
他要在两点去见供货人
He's supposed to meet his supplier at 2:00.
我们得跟着他
We have to follow him.
小鬼头  保密工作到家啊
Tricky little bastard, keeping his identity a secret.
年龄大他一倍的毒贩都没这么精明
He's better than most dealers twice his age.
我一定向他转告你对他
I'll be sure and tell him how impressed you are
犯罪手段的欣赏
with his criminal aptitude.
贝克纳刚刚侵入迦勒的账号  警探
Beckman just broke into Caleb's account, Detective.
他把一个名叫17-6-21的文件拷到了优盘上
He's copying a file named 17-6-21 onto a thumb drive.
无论迦勒做的是什么
Whatever Caleb's making...
他老师对此的兴趣  超出学术范围了
his teacher's interest in it... is far from academic.
菲普斯先生
Oh, Mr. Phipps!
我正赶着出去呢
Look, I'm kind of on my way somewhere.
我只是想把东西还给你
I just wanted to return something of yours.
你昨天落下了
You dropped this yesterday.
你别再翻垃圾桶了  斯威夫特先生
You really got to stop going through the trash, Mr. Swift.
我以前也做过编程
You know, I used to do a little coding myself.
你这段非常出色
That's an elegant string you have.
但我觉得如果你想要用
But it occurs to me that if you want
多线程编法
to implement multi-threading,
用原子变量更好
you'd do better to use atomic variables.
个人想法
Just a thought.
等等  这样  这样可以
Wait, that-- that works.
是的  所以我才如此建议
Yes, that's why I suggested it.
谢谢
Thanks.
希望你随身带了适用的武器  警探
I hope you have your service weapon with you, Detective.
带了  我还给你拿了台机关枪呢
Yeah, I got you a machine gun too.
真幽默  警探  别跟丢了他
Very funny, Detective. Let's try not to lose him.
罗马
Yo, Roman.
在吗
You here?
天啊
Oh, jeez.
你是为这而来的  是吧
That's what you came for, right?
说说看
So tell me...
你这么聪明的孩子为什么会蠢到
why would a kid like you do something so stupid
敢到我地盘上的学校里贩
like dealing at a school in my neighborhood?
那是洛伦佐  迭戈和罗尼以前的老大
That's Lorenzo, all right, Diego and Ronnie's old boss.
有啥计划
What's the plan?
我靠
Crap.
罗马遭受这小意外之前
You know, before he had his little accident here...
告诉我说你想
Roman was telling me how you're just trying
弄笔钱  准备出远门
to score some bank to take a big trip.
真的吗
That true?
是的
Yeah.
把卖给我客人的货款一分不少地还给我
You pay back every dime you made selling to my customers,
我就放你四肢俱全地出城
I'll let you leave town intact.
就在这里  明晚八点
Be back here tomorrow night, 8:00 p.m.,
否则我去找你算账
or I'll come find you.
你让我一天内怎么弄到那么多现金
How do you expect me to score that kind of cash in a day?
冷静
Relax.
好吧  我去  抢个银行好了
All right, I'll... rob a bank or something.
我欣赏你
I like you.
够
You got brass.
但如果明晚你没出现
But you don't show tomorrow night...
打碎的就远不止是你的腿了
break a lot more than your legs.
这孩子很坚强
Kid's got it tough.
但跟毒贩较劲儿
But picking a fight with a drug dealer?
天才办傻事啊
A dumb move for a genius.
为什么一个前途无量的年轻人
Why would a young man with such potential
甘为一点毒资孤注一掷呢
risk it all just to get some easy drug money?
我认为问题不是钱
I don't think it's about the money.
而是他的哥哥
I think it's about the brother.
瑞安・菲普斯死亡那晚的调度报告
Dispatch transcripts from the night Ryan Phipps died.
填报告的站警一开始申请支援
Now the transit cop who filed the report called for backup...
因为迦勒最初报告说
because Caleb initially reported
有两名年轻人挤瑞安
that two youths got into a shoving match with Ryan,
把他推下的轨道
pushed him onto the tracks.
但是警察随后取消了支援申请
But the officer cancelled the backup call
写成是意外事故
and filed an accident report instead.
为什么迦勒要改变说法呢
Why would Caleb change his story?
也许他认识凶手
Maybe he knew the killers.
也许他想要自己找他们复仇
Maybe he was thinking about taking care of them himself.
迭戈和罗尼吗
Diego and Ronnie?
他操纵那些二货
He's manipulating those morons.
让他们为他贩毒
Got 'em running drugs for him,
还傻傻地被蒙在鼓里
and they don't even know it.
贝克纳在专心研究什么呢
What's Beckner so absorbed in?
是迦勒的作品
That's Caleb's work.
霍华德  我是克里斯
Howard, it's Chris.
我们今晚见下面好吗
Can you still meet up tonight?
我带去的东西肯定会让你大吃一惊
I think you'll be impressed with what you see.
太好了  那边见
Great. I'll see you there.
-计划有变  警探  -我猜猜
- Change of plans, Detective. - Let me guess.
你要我一个人盯着这小爱因斯坦一整晚
You need me to keep an eye on little Einstein, myself, tonight.
随时向我报告
Keep me posted.
风投公司的合伙人先生
So, Mr. Venture Capital Firm Partner...
初级合伙人
Junior partner.
离豪华大办公室还远着呢
Long way from the corner office.
还是得步步小心
Still have to watch my step.
-谨慎选项目啊  -我明白
- Pick my projects carefully. - I get it.
你要是看了这个
When you see this...
那就让我看看吧  克里斯
Well, then, let's-- let's just see it, Chris,
看完我就能回去见老婆孩子了
so I can get back to my wife and kids.
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
国会图书馆
The library of congress.
什么
What?
235兆兆的内容
235 terabytes on--
存在这一个优盘中
on one thumb drive?
互联网正受困于流媒体
The internet's choking on streaming video.
需要新的压缩算法
They're gonna need a new compression algorithm
以保持增长
to continue growing.
我成功了
And I've got it.
我只需要一家像你们这样的公司注资
All I need is an investment from a firm like yours
帮我启动
to help me get it off the ground.
那个  是这样的  克里斯
So...here's the thing, Chris.
我还记得你大学的编码水平
I remember your code from back in college.
你也就是中上水平
You were a medium talent at best.
克里斯・贝克纳不可能
There is no way that that Chris Beckner
设计出如此非凡的东西
designed something this extraordinary.
跟我们的老朋友不同
Unlike our old friends,
大学并非我的巅峰
I didn't peak in college.
这么说没其他人知道这个项目
So no one else knows about this project?
程序员  开发员
Programmers? Developers?
或其他的牵扯
No other entanglements?
我肯定
I can guarantee it.
但愿如此吧
Well, let's hope so.
因为我也不想有人拦住你拿到一张
Because I would hate for anyone to come between you
我相信是天文数字的支票
and what I believe is going to be a very large check.
终于查到了那位站警  墨菲
Finally tracked down that transit cop, Murphy.
就是那位迦勒的哥哥死时第一个到现场的
The one who was first on the scene when Caleb's brother died.
已经给他留了信息
Left a message for him to come down
他换岗后就来八局
to the Eighth after his shift.
说到这个  那孩子呢
Speaking of which, where's the kid now?
在到处挪钱  数目巨大
He's moving money around, large amounts.
准备现金给洛伦佐吗
Getting the cash to pay off Lorenzo?
不  他在设信托基金
No, he set up some kind of a trust,
把所有的钱都存进去了
and he's pouring all his money into it.
也许他在考虑出那趟
Maybe he's thinking about taking that trip
他一直挂在嘴边的远门了
he's always talking about.
被复制的手机
克里斯・贝克纳
发短信给迦勒・菲普斯
今晚八点学校见面好吗
贝克纳刚给迦勒发了短信
Beckner just texted Caleb.
他想晚上八点见面
He wants to meet at 8:00 tonight.
那时他正好应该去见洛伦佐
The same time he's supposed to meet Lorenzo.
就算用量子力学算
And quantum physics notwithstanding,
他也没法分身两处
he can't be in two places at once.
除非我说对了  这孩子另有计划
Unless I'm right, and this kid's got a plan,
没时间应付两面来敌
time's running out on two fronts.
对他来说走为上策
Maybe skipping town's the best thing for him.
我们也正好可以专心救你家那位出去
Then we could focus some on getting your pal out of lockup.
里瑟先生能照顾好自己  警探
Mr. Reese can take care of himself, Detective.
现在  他有贵人相助
And right now, he's in very capable hands.
卡特警探
Detective Carter,
抓紧时间  那位还在里克岛监狱里呢
time is ticking away fast for our friend in Rikers.
别担心  我心里有数
Don't worry. I know what to do.
又来了
Here you go.
抱歉  宝贝
Sorry, honey.
明天我就会好起来的
I'll be better tomorrow.
我保证
I promise.
是啊
Yeah.
明天一切都会好起来的  妈
Everything's gonna be better tomorrow, ma.
我是弗斯科警探
Detective Fusco.
提醒一下今晚我需要你的帮助
I just want to remind you that I need your help tonight.
迦勒有两个约会
Caleb has two appointments,
我们不知道他要去哪个
and we have no idea which one he intends to keep.
我会去
I'll be there.
你有事找我
You wanted to speak with me?
是的  坐吧  墨菲警官
Yeah, have a seat, Officer Murphy.
之前也说了  我
Like I said, I'm, uh...
在跟个悬案
working on a cold case.
乘客被推
Commuter got pushed.
在找相关案件  发现了这个
Looking for related cases, this popped up.
瑞安・菲普斯
Ryan Phipps.
上边说你是第一个到现场的
Says here you were first on the scene?
对  没错
Yeah, that's right.
那孩子还有六个月就要满十八岁了
Kid was six months shy of his 18th birthday.
跟他弟弟迦勒一起回家
Coming home with his little brother Caleb.
瑞安有点哄闹  喝了点酒
Ryan was horsing around, drinking a little bit.
滑下轨道  被撞了
Slipped on the tracks and got clipped.
是是  我记得
Yeah, yeah, I remember.
那案子令人痛苦
It was a rough one.
因为死者是孩子
Because it was a kid?
还是因为你没有完整上报
Or because you didn't report the whole story?
我知道有孩子把瑞安推下轨道
I know about the kids who pushed Ryan on the tracks.
我不是警探  警探
I'm no detective, Detective.
我只是个小站警
I'm just a lowly transit cop.
我这辈子见识的也不少了
I seen a lot of things in my time.
我做过很多让我后悔的决定
And I made a lot of decisions I regret.
但这个我永不后悔
This is not one of those times.
要是迦勒变成杀人凶手你也许就要后悔了
You may regret it when Caleb becomes a killer.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你认为复仇就能帮迦勒缓解
You think revenge is gonna make Caleb feel better
亲眼见到哥哥惨死之痛吗
about seeing his brother die?
完全不靠谱  警探
You're a long ways off, Detective.
那就告诉我点靠谱的
Then give me some directions.
我之前对那孩子施压
You know, I did to the kid
就像你现在对我
what you're doing to me right now.
当我让他描述另外几名孩子的情况时
When I asked him for descriptions of the other kids...
说法变来变去
kept changing it up.
根本没有另外的孩子
There were no other kids.
没有
No.
只是俩兄弟喝醉了
Just two brothers drinking.
无聊了
Bored.
等着坐车回家
Waiting for a train to go home.
所以就赌彼此  敢不敢穿轨道
So they dare each other to, uh...cross the tracks.
就是看火车来之前你能来回
You know, how many times you can cross back and forth
穿几次轨道
before a train comes?
瑞安不想输给自己的弟弟
Well, Ryan doesn't want to lose to his little brother.
一个孩子穿过了  另一个没穿过
One kid makes it, the other kid doesn't.
我不知道算谁赢了
I don't know who got the better deal.
所以我告诉他我在报告里会略去不写
So I told him I'd leave all that out of the report,
只写是意外事故
write it up as an accident,
让他为自己保密
and for him to keep it to himself.
无论他怎么告诉他的妈妈
So no matter what he had to tell his mom...
或者警察  或者上帝
or the cops, or God himself...
他哥哥也不会复生了
nothing was gonna bring his brother back.
要怎么说呢
What can I tell you?
有些事就是无法挽回
Some things you can't fix.
我刚和墨菲谈过了
I just talked to Murphy.
他哥哥的死是场意外事故
The brother's death was an accident,
但听起来迦勒为此自责
but it sounds like Caleb blames himself for it.
这可有问题了  警探
Well, that's a problem, Detective,
因为我跟丢迦勒了
Because I lost Caleb.
他上了一辆公车  我还没上去车就开走了
He got on a city bus, and it left before I could catch up.
你开玩笑呢
You're kidding me.
也许我需要得提醒你一下鄙人所能颇多
May I remind you that of the many things I'm equipped to do,
但追踪绝非其中之一
pursuit would not be chief among them.
我们现在唯一的选择就是等在迦勒
Our only option now is to wait for Caleb
可能出现的两个地方
at the two places he's likeliest to turn up.
我去学校监视贝克纳
I'll stake out Beckner at the high school.
你盯那位被侵权的毒犯
You keep an eye out for our aggrieved drug dealer.
叫上所有人  砍死那小子
Get everyone, and hunt that kid down!
那孩子没出现  洛伦佐想要他命了
Our boy is a no-show, and Lorenzo wants his head.
你去找那孩子
You worry about the kid.
我来搞定洛伦佐
I'll take care of Lorenzo.
他也没在这里  警探
He's not here either, Detective.
我可能来晚了
I may be too late.
斯威夫特  你在这儿干嘛
Swift, what are you doing here?
我也想问你同样的问题
I was gonna ask you the same.
-我把论文丢在了  -住口吧
- I-I left some papers on-- - Stop it!
我看到你侵入了迦勒的账号
I saw you break into Caleb's account
拷了他的文件
and copy his files.
你就如此自甘堕落吗
Is that what you're willing to stoop to?
偷学生的作品冒充自己的成果
Stealing the work of a student and passing it off as your own?
我犯不着在这里
I am not gonna stand here
听任代课老师指责我剽窃
and be accused of plagiarism by some substitute teacher.
再说  我干嘛要拷C分学生的作品
Besides, why would I copy work off of a "C"-grade student?
因为迦勒绝非平庸之辈
Because Caleb is anything but average.
你心里清楚
And you know it.
所以你才把他的作品给你朋友看
That's why you took his work to your friend.
迦勒
Caleb...
几个月前让我
approached me a few months ago
看他正在做的这个项目
about this project he was working on.
我本来很怀疑  但当我看到编码后
I was skeptical, but when I...saw his code
简直不敢相信自己的眼睛  所以我决定帮他
I couldn't believe my eyes, so I decided to help him.
-用自己独揽来帮他  -不
- By cutting him out of it. - No.
他只想要钱
All he wanted was some money up front
准备出远门
for this trip that he wants to take.
说他不想要任何荣誉
Said he didn't even want any credit.
你怎么能同意呢
Why on earth would you agree to that?
我没有
I didn't.
自己看
Read it for yourself.
迦勒会得到所有的荣誉
Caleb gets all the credit.
我是为了要省事点
It was just easier for me to...
才由我出面给他看
pitch the idea with him myself...
好拿到启动资金
get some capital...
然后真正的幕后高手会现身
and then reveal the true brain behind it.
他分给我一半  另一半要我
He offered me half if I put the other half
存入他为他妈妈开设的信托基金
in a trust that he set up for his mom.
但我会都给他
But I'm giving him the whole thing.
这是所有17-6-21的钱
All the money from 17-6-21.
17-6-21
17-6-21?
这是他给程序的命名
It's the name he gave the program.
他说这是什么纪念
He said it was some kind of dedication.
我告诉你  六个月后
Look, I am telling you, six months from now,
迦勒会成为全国最有钱的十八岁少年
Caleb is going to be the richest 18-year-old in the country.
不
No.
不  他不会
No, he won't.
获取档案
2010年7月
获取关联文件
纽约警局
纽约警局档案  2010年7月
会话分析
语言识别
调度  我是墨菲警官
Dispatch? Officer Murphy,
获取档案
2010年7月
地铁死亡案
regarding the subway fatality.
获取档案
2010年7月
大西洋大道站
取消支援请求
10-80 on the backup request.
警官  取消支援请求吗
10-5, officer. Cancel backup request?
确定
Affirmative.
这里有人坐吗
This seat taken?
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
你很聪明  迦勒
You're so smart, Caleb.
问点你不知道答案的问题吧
Ask me something you don't know.
行为鲁莽
The thing about being reckless...
甘愿冒险
taking chances...
犯下了很多错误
is that you make a lot of mistakes,
造成了很多不幸
cause a lot of grief.
准备向我宣讲所谓错误
Gonna start lecturing me on mistakes?
要我吸取教训
How I need to live and learn?
继续前行
Move on?
真鼓舞人心  斯威夫特先生
That's really inspiring, Mr. Swift.
我要站到桌子上为你鼓掌
I'd stand up on my desk and clap for you.
不过
But...
不
No.
你的错误  和我一样
Your mistakes, like mine,
成就了今天的你
are part of who you are now.
你无法弃之前行
You can't move on from that.
相信我
Believe me.
我犯过很多错
I've made a sizable number.
但是
But...
有时错误也会给你惊喜
sometimes your mistakes can surprise you.
譬如说  我最大的错误
My biggest mistake, for instance...
把我带到了这里
brought me here.
在这个时刻
At exactly this moment...
在你可能需要帮助的时刻
when you might need some help.
17年6个月零21天的生命
17 years, 6 months and 21 days into your life.
你哥哥死去的年龄
The age at which your brother died.
也是你选择结束自己生命的年龄
The age you've chosen to end your life too.
17-6-21
17-6-21.
所以你看
So, you see...
也许你我之间是有共鸣的
maybe you and I are connected.
两个鲁莽的人
Two reckless people.
是吗  那有什么用
Yeah? Then what's the use?
我们只会破坏
We're just gonna keep breaking things...
一次又一次
over and over.
为什么不替大家省掉不幸呢
Why not save everyone the grief?
整个世界
The thing about the world is
没有多余的部分
that it doesn't have any extra pieces.
就像π  包含所有
It's like pi. It contains everything.
你去掉了一块
You remove a single piece...
就不成圆
No circle.
你的鲁莽  你的错误
Your recklessness, your mistakes,
使得你在他们说出
are the reason why, when they say
"你无法改变世界"时  拒绝相信
"You can't change the world," you won't listen.
这个世界
The world is better off
因为你我的存在才更好  迦勒  而非相反
with both of us in it, Caleb, rather than the alternative
是吗  你能确定
Yeah? You sure about that?
是的  你妈妈因为你的存在才更好
Yes, and your mom is better off with you in it.
如果你认为钱能代替你
If you think money can replace you...
你算错了
you haven't seen the whole equation.
说这句话的人曾以为
Take it from someone who thought
自己离开能够让其他人过得轻松点
that leaving would make it easier on everyone...
结果却并非如此
and then learned otherwise.
再说一遍
Say it to me again.
说慢点
Slowly.
根据实验室检验结果
According to the lab results,
我们从这四人身上提取的DNA
none of the DNA we took from these four men
和数据库的任何DNA都不匹配
matches any of the DNA in our database.
他们是清白的  长官  四个都是
They're clean, Sir. All four of 'em.
把所有的样本都送到匡提科
I want every one of those samples sent to Quantico,
检测DNA联合索引系统  检测是否有篡改
reviewed through CODIS, and inspected for tampering.
他们搞鬼了
They got to it.
虽然不知道怎么做的  但那群混蛋搞鬼了
I don't know how, but those bastards got to it.
快去
Go.
还有一件事
One more thing.
把卡特叫来
Get me Carter.
你应该小心处理你的编码
You really ought to be more careful with your code.
谢谢
Thanks.
我成长于冷战时期
I grew up during the Cold War...
那时电脑网络
when computer networks were just a gleam
在国防部眼里仅是一道微光
in the eye of the Department of Defense.
一切都非黑即白
Things seemed more black and white then.
阿帕网是新领域
Arpanet was the new frontier.
直到一个小孩用自制电脑
Till a kid with a homemade computer
彻底颠覆了整个世界
turned the whole thing inside out.
我要说的是
All I'm saying is...
现在是一个新的时代
it's a new era now,
一切都开始变得怪诞
and things are about to get really weird.
你要藏好你的编码
So you should keep your code close to your vest.
慎选朋友
And pick your friends wisely.
π
Pi.
前3000个数字
The first 3,000 digits.
我的号码就在其中
My number's in there somewhere.
你很聪明  会找出来
You're smart, you'll figure it out.
等等  那位黑客
Wait, uh, the hacker.
成功溜走的那位
The one who got away?
你怎么知道他用的是自制电脑
How'd you know he did that with a homemade computer?
我读过所有的研究材料  没人提起过
I've read all that research. No one's ever mentioned that.
我肯定是从哪儿听说的
I must have heard it somewhere.
卡特警探
Detective Carter?
关在里克岛的那位被释放了吗
Has our friend in Rikers been released?
快了  我现在去见他
Almost. I'm going to meet him now.
你的DNA和他们要找的人不匹配
Your DNA wasn't a match for whoever they're looking for.
我们现在就释放你
We'll be processing you out momentarily.
停住
Stop right there.
根据国防授权法案
These men have all been classified
这几人被判定为"非法武装人员"
as "Unlawful Combatants" by the AUMF.
在我们确定他们不会
Until we can establish that they're not a threat
对国家安全造成威胁前
to national security,
他们哪儿都不能去
they're not going anywhere.
把他带回去
Put him back.
我正想见你
Just the person I wanted to see.
怎么了
What is going on?
我以为证据表明这些人是清白的
I thought the evidence cleared these guys.
DNA  指纹  都太干净了
The DNA, the fingerprints, it's all too neat.
我无数次想要把他
I've been burned too many times
绳之以法
trying to bring this man to justice.
现在我只有一个人能够相信
There's only one person that I know I can trust anymore:
你
You.
你从开始就一直在追捕他
You've been chasing him from the beginning.
我们只剩最后一个机会了  警探
And we've only got one shot left at him, Detective.
他要是从这里离开  我们就再也见不到他了
If he walks out of here, we're never gonna see him again.
我知道你在伊拉克时是高级审讯官
I know you were a senior interrogator in Iraq.
是时候动用军事技能了
It's time to put those military skills to use.
我要你审问他们每一个人
I want you to interrogate every last one of these men.
找出他们是谁  知道些什么
Find out who they are, what they know.
从他开始
Start with him.